Charles B. Davenport Papers ca.1903-1940 Mss.B.D27
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Cold Spring Harbor Series, 1899-1946; 20 linear feet (Box 98-136)
  - Subseries B. Records of Assistants, 1904-1946 (Box 107-136)
    - State Charities Aid Association, 2 folders (Box 131)
      - Protection of the State's Unfortunates, 1919-1929 (Box 131)
    - Station for Experimental Evolution, 1904-1923 (Box 131-132)
      Bibliographical matters; Business; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Eugenics; Invitations; Requests for reprints; Station for Experimental Evolution -- Annual reports; Station for Experimental Evolution -- Beginnings; Station for Experimental Evolution -- Five-year plan (1920); Station for Experimental Evolution -- History; Station for Experimental Evolution -- Library; Station for Experimental Evolution -- Plans; Station for Experimental Evolution -- Staff
      - Accounts, 1904-1921; 16 folders (Box 131)
      - Annual Report of Director, 1917 (Box 131)
        *Plough, Harold H.
        - Annual Report of Director, 1918 (Box 131)
        - Annual Report of Director, 1919; 3 folders (Box 131)
      - Annual Reports, 1920 (Box 131)
        *Banker, H. J.
        Banta, A. M.
        Belling, John
        Corner, G. W.
        Laughlin, H. H.
        MacDowell, E. C.
        Riddle, Oscar
      - Bibliography, 2 folders (Box 132)
      - Botanical Investigator, 1915 (Box 132)
        *East, Edward
        Sinnott, Edmund W.
      - Budgets, 6 folders (Box 132)
        - Folder 1, 1905-1913 (Box 132)
        - Folder 2, 1914-1916 (Box 132)
        - Folder 3, 1917-1919 (Box 132)
        - Folder 4, 1920 (Box 132)
        - Folders 5-6, 1921; 2 folders (Box 132)
      - Committee on Sex (Box 132)
      - Davenport, C. B. - Notes, 1913 (Box 132)
      - Family Records Form (Box 132)
      - Five Year Plan, 1920; 2 folders (Box 132)
        *Banta, A. M.
        Blakeslee, A. F.
        Fish, H. D.
        Harris, J. A.
        Little, C. C.
        MacDowell, C.
      - Gifts (Box 132)
      - Goose Island Title Search (Box 132)
      - History (Box 132)
      - Insurance Policies (Box 132)
      - Library (Box 132)
      - Mailing Lists (Box 132)
      - Maintenance (Box 132)
      - Memos (Box 132)
      - Opening 1904, Invitations, 5 folders (Box 132)
      - Plans and Specifications, 4 blueprints (Box 132)
      - Salaries, 1911-1912 (Box 132)
      - Staff (Box 132)
        Previously found under "Agreements".
      - Staff technicians (Box 132)
    - Steggerda, Inez Dunkelberger (Box 133)
    - Steggerda, Morris, 1925-1942; 38 folders (614 items) (Box 133-134)
      Anthropology; Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Eugenics; Graduate study; Human genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication; Race crossing; Steggerda, Morris; Teaching -- Smith College; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
      - 1925-1926 (January - March) (Box 133)
      - 1926 (April - September) (Box 133)
      - 1926 (October) (Box 133)
      - 1926 (November - December) (Box 133)
      - 1927 (January - February) (Box 133)
      - 1927 (March) (Box 133)
      - 1927 (April) (Box 133)
      - 1927 (May - June) (Box 133)
      - 1927 (July) (Box 133)
      - 1927 (August - December) (Box 133)
      - 1928 (March - June) (Box 133)
      - 1928 (July - December) (Box 133)
      - 1929 (January - April) (Box 133)
      - 1929 (May - November) (Box 133)
      - 1930 (Box 133)
      - 1931 (January - May) (Box 133)
      - 1931 (June - November) (Box 133)
      - 1932 (January - May) (Box 133)
      - 1932 (June - October) (Box 133)
      - 1932-1933 Annual Report, 4 folders (Box 133)
      - 1933 (Box 133)
      - 1934 (January - June) (Box 133)
      - 1934 (August - December) (Box 133)
      - 1935 (January - March) (Box 133)
      - 1935 (April - December) (Box 133)
      - 1936 (January - February) (Box 133)
      - 1936 (March - June) (Box 133)
      - 1936 (July - December) (Box 133)
      - 1937 (Box 133)
      - 1938 (Box 133)
      - 1939 (Box 134)
      - 1940 (Box 134)
      - 1941 (Box 134)
      - 1942 (March - July) (Box 134)
      - 1942 (August - December) (Box 134)
    - Stein, Kathryn F. (Box 134)
      *Morgan, Ann
    - Steward, Ethel H. (Box 134)
    - Stokes, W. E. D. (William Earl Dodge), 1910-1926; 19 folders (377 items) (Box 134)
      Biographical and personal data; Cancer, chemotherapy; Eugenics; Genetics -- Horses; Human genetics; Political issues; Poultry genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science
      - 1910 (Box 134)
      - 1911 (Box 134)
      - 1912 (Box 134)
      - 1913 (Box 134)
      - 1914 (Box 134)
      - 1915 (Box 134)
      - 1916 (Box 134)
      - 1917 (Box 134)
      - 1918 (January - April) (Box 134)
      - 1918 (May - September) (Box 134)
      - 1919 (Box 134)
      - 1920 (Box 134)
      - 1921 (January - March) (Box 134)
      - 1921 (June - December) (Box 134)
      - 1922 (Box 134)
      - 1923-1924 (Box 134)
      - 1925 (January - September) (Box 134)
      - 1925 (October - December) (Box 134)
      - 1926 (Box 134)
    - Taylor, A. B. (Box 134)
    - Ter Louw, Adrian (Box 134)
    - Thaler, Joseph Ira (Box 134)
    - Toda, Kenji (Box 134)
    - Toof, Mary Esther (Box 134)
    - Transeau, Gertrude H. (Box 135)
    - Tuthill, Tracy Emerson (Box 135)
    - Twining, Ruth (Box 135)
    - Ullian, Silka Stocker (Box 135)
    - U. S. Army, 5 folders (Box 135)
      - Anthropometric Data, 1919-1920; 4 folders (Box 135)
      - Seventy-Seventh Division, 1925 (Box 135)
    - United States Department of Agriculture, 1907-1926; 9 folders (Box 135)
      - Bureau of Animal Industry (Box 135)
      - Bureau of Biological Survey (Box 135)
      - Bureau of Entomology (Box 135)
      - Bureau of Plant Industry (Box 135)
      - Bureau of Soils (Box 135)
      - Division of Publications, 1904-1922; 2 folders (Box 135)
      - Library (Box 135)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 135)
    - U.S. Department of Commerce and Labor (Box 135)
    - U.S. Department of State (Box 135)
    - Valle, J. A. Lopez de (Box 135)
    - Vicari, Amelia M. (Box 135)
    - Vial, E. E. (Box 135)
    - Warren, Donald C. (Box 135)
    - Warren, Paul A. (Box 135)
    - Watson, Isabelle (Box 135)
    - Watt, Betty P. (Box 135)
    - Watts, Mary T., 1922-1925; 2 folders (Box 135)
    - Weeks, David Fairchild, 1910-1927; 6 folders (168 items) (Box 135)
      Behavioral genetics, IQ; Eugenics; Human genetics -- Epilepsy; International Congress of Eugenics -- First Congress; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
      - Folder 1, 1910 (Box 135)
      - Folders 2-4, 1911; 3 folders (Box 135)
      - Folder 5, 1912-1913 (Box 135)
      - Folder 6, 1914-1927 (Box 135)
    - Weinstein, Alexander (Box 135)
    - Welch, Donald S. (Box 135)
    - White, Clinton (Box 135)
    - White, Edna (Box 135)
    - White, Harry (Box 135)
    - White, Ralph K. (Box 135)
    - Whitney, Leon F., 1922-1927; 13 folders (Box 136)
      Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Eugenics; Genetics -- Dogs; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; Political issues; Poultry genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
      - Folder 1, 1922-1923 (Box 136)
      - Folder 2, 1924 (Box 136)
      - Folders 3-5, 1925; 3 folders (Box 136)
      - Folders 6-9, 1926; 4 folders (Box 136)
      - Folders 10-13, 1927; 4 folders (Box 136)
    - Wickens, Constance (Box 136)
    - Wiggam, A. E. (Albert Edward), 1919-1928; 3 folders (59 items) (Box 136)
      Eugenics; Human genetics; Publication
    - Wiley, J. and Sons, 1904-1931; 2 folders (Box 136)
    - Williams, Frankwood E., 1917-1930; 2 folders (Box 136)
    - Williams, Louise (Box 136)
    - Windle, William (Box 136)
    - Winkley, Ruth (Box 136)
    - Witter, Howard (Box 136)
    - Wood, Thelma R. (Box 136)
    - Wright, Mabel D. (Box 136)
    - Wullen, Hilda H. (Box 136)
  - Subseries C. Photographs, 1900-1936
    A small collection of photographs, consisting primarily of formal portraits of Davenport.
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, 3/4 length, informal, seated, ca. 1930
    - Charles Benedict Davenport with wife, young boy and two young women, full length, informal, standing outside in front of window and bush., 1916 Aug.
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, bust, formal, 1914
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, bust, formal, 1936
    - Charles Benedict Davenport and Gertrude C. Davenport, full length, informal, standing outside, 1902 Nov. 16
    - Banquet tendered physicians and delegates to the national Conference on Race Betterment by the Battle Creek Sanitarium, portrait in dining hall, 1914 Jan. 10
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, full length, informal, standing outside on steps in front of door, 1929
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, bust, formal, 1900
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, bust, profile, informal, seated at desk writing, ca. 1936
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, bust, formal, 1936
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, portrait, ca. 1903
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, portrait, ca. 1903
    - Charles Benedict Davenport, portrait. Appears enfeebled by age and illness, 1929
    - Charles B. Davenport, 1/2 length portrait, formal, n.d.
    - Charles B. Davenport, 1/2 length portrait, formal, ca. 1929
    - Charles B. Davenport, bust length portrait, formal, 1914
    - Charles B. Davenport, 3/4 view, bust length portrait, formal, n.d.
      Note on verso: "Return to E.C. MacDowell, Cold Spring Harbor, NY."
    - Charles Benedict Davenport and cat, 1915